어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri Martial Artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예자 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri Martial Artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi enters-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
시라누이의 함정에 빠진 무사시는 독 때문에 마비되고 말았다.
Musashi fell into Shiranui's trap, and was paralyzed by poison.
그리고 코지로는 애도 모노호시자오가 부러져, 실의의 밑바닥으로.
And Kojirō got his beloved sword Monohoshizao broken, and fell into the very bottom of despair.
어떻게든 재기시켜 주려는 무사시와 센히메였지만.
Musashi and Senhime were trying to recover Kojirō,
어허, 잘 안 되고 있었다.
why, it wasn't working out so well.
지금 되살아나는
전설의 검이오
The Reviving
Legendary Sword
애도 모노호시자오가 부서진 코지로는 마치 혼이 빠져나간 듯 계속 실연에 빠져 있었다.
After having his beloved sword Monohashizao broken, Kojirō was deep in despair, as if his spirit was lost.
코지로?
Kojirō?
나, 가오!
I will go-dasu !
간다니 어디에?
Go to where?
당연한 것이오! 아마쿠사도에 가오!
It's obvious-dasu! I'm going to Amakusa Island-dasu!
시라누이 일족에게 죽으러 가는 것과 마찬가지요.
It's just like going there just to be killed by Shiranul Clan-gowasu.
그런 생각을 하면 아무것도 못 하오! 무엇보다도, 나, 저런 코지로를 보고만 있을 수는 없소.
With that kind of way of thinking, you can't do anything-dasu! Most of all, I can't stand seeing Kojirō like that-dasu!
무사시. 네가 바보라서 쿠마손의 함정에 빠져서 이렇게 된 것이다. 난 싫었다.
Musashi. This all happened because you're foolish enough to be fallen into Kumason's trap. I did not wanted to join.
무사시 잘못이다. 무사시 잘못.
It's all Musashi's fault. Musashi was wrong.
재기 불능인가.
Is he not recoverable-gowasu?
사과해도 언제까지나 날 원망할 생각이오.
Even if I apologize, he'll going to blame me forever-dasu.
모노호시자오는 정말로 자신의 분신 같은 것이었으니 말이야.
Monohoshizao was truly like his other self.
그러니까 책임을 지고 내가 모노호시자오에 견줄 비검을 아마쿠사도에 찾으러 가오!
That's why I'm going to be responsible and go to Amakusa Island to find that secret sword on a par with Monohoshizao!
잠깐, 무사시. 마음은 알겠는데 위험해.
Wait, Musashi. I understand you, but it's too dangerous.
아, 나는 가야만 하오. 막지 마시오, 센짱! 그 손을 놓으시오!
Oh, but I must go-dasu. Do not stop me-dasu! Unhand me-dasu!
놓아! 놓아! 놓으시오!
Unhand me! Unhand me! Let me go-dasu!
애초에 안 잡았어.
I didn't hold you at the first place.
바보 자식.
Idiot.
어라?
Huh?
마침 딱 잘 됐소. 이 배 빌리겠소!
This is just right-dasu! I'll borrow this ship-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
모든 건 무사시 잘못입니다.
Everything is Musashi's fault.
시끄럽소...
How noisy-dasu...
무사시. 네 잘못이다. 무사시! 무사시!
Musashi! It's your fault. Musashi! Musashi!
코지로, 용서해 주시오...
Kojirō, please forgive me-dasu...
꿈이었소...
It was just a dream-dasu...
아야! 아프오! 으악! 살려주시오!
Ouch! That hurts-dasu! Waaah! Help me!
아팠소...
That hurt...
여기가 아마쿠사 섬이오. 수상한 분위기는 어디에도 없소...
This must be that Amakusa Island-dasu. I don't feel anything suspicious-dasu...
그러고 보니 어젯밤부터 아무것도 안 먹었소.
I just remembered that I didn't eat anything since last night-dasu.
실례하오! 이 주변에 단고집 있소?
Excuse me-dasu! Is there a dango house around here-dasu?
누구 있소?
Hello-dasu?
외출이오...
Absent, I guess...
실례하오! 이 주변에 단고집 있소?
Excuse me-dasu! Is there a dango house around here-dasu?
나, 배고파서 죽을 것 같소.
I'm gonna die of hunger-dasu...
누구 있소?!
Is anyone there-dasu?!
잠깐 기다리시오!
Wait for me-dasu!
어, 어디 갔소...
W- where did they go-dasu?
아, 배고파서 못 움직이오.
I'm too hungry to move-dasu.
누구 있소?!
Anybody there-dasu?!
나, 아무거나 좋으니까 먹고 싶소! 꼭!
I want to eat anything possible-dasu! Please!
누구이오!
Who's there-dasu?!
함정인 것 같소. 나, 적에게 둘러싸였소!
It looks like a trap-dasu. I'm surrounded by enemies-dasu!
관두시오!
Stop it-dasu!
아빠 엄마 돌려줘!
Give my daddy and mommy back!
시라누이 일족 따위 해치워버릴 거야!
We'll get rid of any Shiranui Clan!
멈추시오! 사람 잘못 봤소! 나, 시라누이 일족을 해치우기 위해 여기에 왔소!
Stop-dasu! You've got it wrong-dasu! I'm here to take care of Shiranui Clan-dasu!
어? 다들 공격 멈춰!
What? Everyone, stop attacking!
네!
Yeah!
이름을 들으면 아오!
You'll know it when you hear my name-dasu!
나, 지팡구 제일의 카라쿠리 무예가가 되고자 하는 미야모토 마을의 무사시이오!
I am the number one Karakuri martial artist of future of Jipangu, Musashi from Miyamoto village-dasu!
모르오!
Never heard of him-dasu!
그래도, 잘 보면 요새 마을에 덤벼든 놈들하고는 다르네.
But anyway, he does look different from the ones who came to attack the village!
응. 놈들은 다들 눈매가 나빴는데, 이 형은 좋은 눈매야.
Yeah. They looked like they had ill will, but this brother has a good look!
너희들 사람 보는 눈이 있소! 왠지 해 드려야겠소!
You guys do have a discerning eye-dasu! I must do something for you-dasu!
정말?!
Really?!
그래도 그 전에 뭔가 먹게 해 주시오.
But before that, let me eat something-dasu.
맛있소맛있소맛있소!
It's so good!
싹도 맛있소.
Even the leaf is good-dasu.
우리도 잘 먹긴 하는데, 무사시 형처럼 먹는 사람은 처음 봐.
We eat much, but I never saw someone who eat as much as Musashi bro!
정말. 벌써 20개 째야.
Really. He already ate 20!
아, 그렇소. 이 섬에 전설의 비검이 있소?
Oh, right. Is there any legendary secret sword in this island-dasu?
전설의 비검? 그거, 봉황환 말이야?
By that legendary secret sword, do you mean Hououmaru?
봉황환이었소! 어디 있소?
So that was Hououmaru! Where is it?
우리 아빠가 소중하게 관리하고 있었는데 시라누이 일족이 가져갔어.
My dad was taking care of it preciously, but then Shiranui Clan took it.
-뭣이오?!
-한 달 정도 전에.
-What-dasu?!
-About a month ago.
시라누이 일족이 나타나 섬에 있는 모든 사람을 데려가고, 게다가 칼, 괭이, 쟁기 따위를 죄다 빼앗아가 버렸어.
Shiranui Clan has appeared to take all the people on the island, and in addition, they took all the swords, hoes, and spades.
그 때, 어떻게든 우린 도망쳐서 살았어.
During that, we somehow escaped and we're here.
그랬소.
So that's what happened-dasu.
시라누이 일족은 우리 엄마를 어디로 데려갔을까...
I wonder where did that Shiranui Clan take my mommy to...
아빠! 엄마!
Daddy! Mommy!
이카즈치
Ikazuchi
나는 시라누이 일족의 이카즈치다.
I am one of Shiranui Clan, Ikazuchi!
나는 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 될 무사시이오!
I am Musashi, the future number one martial artist of Jipangu!
어라?
Huh?
무사시. 날아 불에 들어오는 여름의 벌레는 네놈을 말하는구나!
Musashi. You are here to rush to your doom!
시끄럽소! 마을 사람들을 어디에 데려갔소!
Shut up-dasu! Where did you take the villagers-dasu?!
알고 싶냐?
Wanna know?
당연하오!
Of course-dasu!
돌려 주진 않을 테지만 어디 있는지는 보여 주지.
I won't free them, but I'll let you know where they are.
내가 싸울 동안 도망치시오.
Run away while I fight-dasu.
알았어. 형 혼자 괜찮아?
Got it. Are you really okay by yourself?
당연하오!
Of course-dasu!
이카즈치 탄을 보여 주겠다!
I'll show you Ikazuchi Shell!
하늘이 부르고 땅이 불렀소! 이 세상의 악을 퇴치할 사내 무사시!
The sky called and the ground called Musashi, the man who will take care of all the evil in this world!
지금 등장하오.
I'm here to fight-dasu.
이천일류 철풍차!
Nitenichiryu: Iron Windmill!
음? 건방진 꼬맹이가! 이카즈치 탄을 맛보아라!
Aren't you an impudent brat?! Take my Ikazuchi Shell!
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
여긴 시라누이 일족의 비밀 공장이오.
This must be the secret factory of Shiranui Clan.
젠장!
Damn!
약속대로 보여줬다. 섬 지하에 있는 마을 사람들을!
I showed them as promised. The villagers are in underground of the island!
이런 곳에서 일이나 시키고 대체 뭘 꾸미고 있소!
Why would you make them work in a place like this-dasu?!
저걸 봐라!
Take a look at that!
신식 대포, 철포를 만들고 있다.
We are making new type cannons and guns.
어? 저렇게 잔뜩?
Huh? That many?
저만큼 있으면 에도토피아를 전멸하는 것도 아주 쉽다!
With that many, it is trivial to annihilate Edotopia!
즉, 천하는 우리 시라누이 일족의 것이다!
Meaning that the world is under Shiranui Clan's hands!
그렇게 되도록 냅둘 것 같소이까! 이 내가 그렇게 하도록 안 두오!
I won't let that happen-dasu! I'll stop you-dasu!
그렇지만 무사시, 아무리 의지가 있어도 죽으면 아무것도 못 한다.
But Musashi, you can't do anything if you die, no matter how deeply you desire.
뭣이오?!
What?!
이건 막 만들어진 철포다. 이 위력을 네게 쏘아 시험해 주마!
This gun was just made. I will test its might by shooting this to you!
으악! 그런 건 시험해 보지 않아도 괜찮소!
Wah! You don't have to test that to find it out!
각오해라!
Hope you're prepared!
안 하오!
I won't!
결국 목숨을 잃는가, 무사시! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Will Musashi finally lose his life?! Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
by Subdivers
당했소!
I got hit!
어? 총알을 넣지 않았군.
Hm? I didn't charge it with ammo.
뭣이오?! 기껏 각오했더니! 어서 쏘시오!
What did you say-dasu?! I tried hard to prepare-dasu! Hurry up and shoot-dasu!
걱정 마라! 지금 곧 저 세상에 보내 주마!
Don't worry! You're going to hell soon!
알겠냐! 이번에야말로 간다!
Understand this! You're going this time!
누구냐!
Who's that?!
음? 네놈은!
Hm? You bastard!
쥬베 씨!
Mr. Jube!
뭐? 쥬베?
What? Jube?
시라누이 일족의 비밀 병기 공장. 단단히 봐 두었다!
I've seen Shiranui Clan's secret weapon factory for sure!
이에야스의 개자식! 어느새 몰래 들어왔나! 그렇지만 네 명줄도 여기까지인 줄 알아라!
Ieyasu's underling! How did you sneak in?! Anyway, know that your life ends now!
쥬베 씨, 고맙소!
Thank you, Mr. Jube!
이 자식이! 먹어라!
How dare you, you bastard?! Take this!
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
멈춰라! 넌 내가 상대한다!
Stop! I'll face you!
흥! 바라던 바라!
Hmph! Just as I wanted!
-멍청한 자식.
-뭐?!
-What a fool.
-What?!
나도 하오!
I'll fight too-dasu!
거기까지다! 무사시! 쥬베!
That's as far as you go, Musashi, Jube!
마을 사람들을 죽이기 싫다면 칼을 내려두어라!
If you don't want to kill the villagers, then put your sword down!
비, 비겁하오!
H- how cowardly!
전투에 비겁하고 자시고 하는 거 없다! 머리 좋은 놈이 이길 뿐이다!
There's no coward or whatsoever in a battle! Whoever is smarter wins, and that's it!
어쩔 수 없군.
We have no choice.
칼을 내려둘 필요는 없소!
There is no need to put your swords down-gowasu!
센짱! 사이고 씨! 코지로! 어째서 여기에!
Sen-chan! Mr. Saigo! Kojirō! How did you get here?!
무사시 혼자서는 걱정되니까 왔어!
We were worried about you, Musashi, especially since you're alone!
자, 시라누이 군, 순순히 무기를 내려두시오.
Now, now, Shiranui, put your weapons down-gowasu.
안됐군. 이라고 하고 싶던 참이지만 그쪽이야말로 헛짓은 관둬라.
Too bad. You're the ones to give up with futile actions.
헛짓이오?
Futile actions-gowasu?
그렇다! 그 철포에는 아직 총알이 들어가 있지 않다!
That's right! There's no ammo in those guns yet!
뭣이?! 곤란하오...
What did you say?! Well, that's bad-gowasu...
모두 무사시 탓이다.
It's all Musashi's fault.
사이고, 코지로, 센히메도 한꺼번에 저 세상에 보낼 수 있다니 경사스러운 일이로다!
Being able to send Saigo, Kojirō, and Senhime along with them to the other world is truly a joyous occasion!
자, 저 놈들을 포박해라!
Go get them!
뭐, 뭔 일이냐, 대체?!
W- what's going on?!
무사시 형, 구하러 왔어!
Musashi bro, we're here to save you!
오, 고맙소!
Thank you-dasu!
무사시 님, 다시 한번 날뛰어 봅시다!
Mr. Musashi, why not rage around again?
그렇소!
You're right!
사이고 씨, 이 틈에 시라누이를 처리해!
Mr. Saigo, deal with those Shiranuis using this chance!
알겠소!
Understood!
다들 활기차구나...
Everyone's so energetic...
체스트!
Chest!
형, 칼 가져왔어!
Bro, we took your swords!
고맙소!
Thank you-dasu!
이치로타!
Ichirota!
아빠! 엄마!
Dad! Mom!
이치로타!
Ichirota!
보고 싶었어!
I wanted to see you!
다들 괜찮구나.
Are everyone alright?
이치로타의 아버지이오! 잘 됐소!
You must be Ichirota's father-dasu! What a relief-dasu!
그나저나, 전설의 비검 봉황환은 괜찮소, 아니면 쇠 부스러기가 되어 버렸소?
By the way, is that legendary secret sword Hououmaru alright-dasu, or did it become scrap iron-dasu?
봉황환만은 숨겨 두었습니다.
Hououmaru is hidden and safe.
잘 됐소! 꼭 코지로에게 양도해 주시면 좋겠소!
Great to know-dasu! I'd like you to give that to Kojirō-dasu.
만약 코지로 님에게 가질 자격이 될 능력이 있다면 괜찮습니다만...
If Mr. Kojirō has a qualifying capacity to have one, then I can...
어? 그 능력이 뭣이오?
Huh? What is that capacity-dasu?
지금까지 수많은 무예가가 봉황환을 보고 오셨지만, 지금까지 그 누구 하나 빼내지 못했습니다.
Until now, numerous martial artists came, looking for Hououmaru, but nobody has ever managed to take it out.
칼이 안 빠지오?
The sword's stuck-dasu...
만약 코지로가 뺄 수 있으면 괜찮소?
If Kojirō can pull it out, can he have it-dasu?
그럴 수도 있겠지만...
That's possible...
시라누이가 불을 지폈소. 다들 달아나쇼!
Shiranui has set up a fire-gowasu. Everyone, escape!
코지로! 어서!
Kojirō! Hurry!
살았소...
We live-dasu...
안심하긴 이르다!
It's too early to relive!
몰살시켜 주겠다!
You'll all be annihilated!
아, 지쳤다.
I'm tired.
코지로도 참...
Kojirō...
봉황환은 어디 있소!
Where is Hououmaru-dasu?!
숨겨 두었으니까 지금 가져 오겠습니다!
It's hidden for now; I'll go take it!
부탁드리오!
Please do so-dasu!
체스트!
Chest!
필살! 가랑이 차기!
Special move! Crotch Kick!
아파?
Did that hurt?
만만찮은 놈들이군!
Pretty tough, eh?!
시라누이 요술 이카즈치 탄!
Shiranui Magic, Ikazuchi Shell!
쥬베 씨! 사이고 씨!
Mr. Jube! Mr. Saigo!
무사시 씨! 봉황환을 가져왔습니다!
Mr. Musashi! I took Hououmaru!
조심하시오!
Watch out-dasu!
원래의 화려하고 아름다운 코지로로 돌아왔어!
Kojirō's back to his original beautiful look!
봉황환이 빠졌소!
He pulled out Hououmaru-dasu!
시라누이 요술 이카즈치 탄!
Shiranui Magic, Ikazuchi Shell!
코지로! 위험하오!
Kojirō! Watch out-dasu!
뭐, 뭔 짓이냐!
W- what are you doing?!
정신 차렸어! 코지로, 괜찮아?
He woke up! Kojirō, are you alright?
잘 됐소!
What a relief-dasu!
나, 난 대체... 어째서...
W- what... was I doing?
몇 시간이고 정신을 잃어서 걱정했어.
You were unconscious for numerous hours. We were so worried!
봉황환을 뺄 수 있었던 데다가 그 검에서 황금의 새를 출현시킨 자라면, 그 자에게 봉황환을 넘기라고 아마쿠사 섬에 구전되어 내려옵니다.
The legends of Amakusa Island say that the one to pull out Hououmaru and
make the Golden Bird appear will take Hououmaru.
그러니까 코지로 씨, 당신에게 이 봉황환을 드리겠습니다.
So, Mr. Kojirō, you can have this Hououmaru.
정말 감사합니다.
Thank you so much.
다만 황금의 새가 나타난 때에는 정신력을 다 소모할 각오를.
But when the Golden Bird appears, be prepared to exhaust your mental powers.
알겠습니다. 이 코지로, 세상을 위해, 사람을 위해, 나아가서는 센히메를 위해, 이 봉황환에 걸맞는 모습을 보여드리겠습니다.
Understood. I, Kojirō, will live up to Hououmaru, not only for the world and for the people, but also for Senhime.
어라, 또 잘난 척 시작했소.
Hey, he began acting cool again-dasu.
그래도 그 쪽이 침울한 코지로보다는 낫소!
But that's still better than depressed Kojirō-dasu!
정말.
Agreed!
모노호시자오의
무덤
Tomb of Monohoshizao
내 반생을 함께한 애도 모노호시자오여. 네가 있어서 이 내가 봉황환을 손에 넣을 수 있었다.
Dear my beloved sword Monohoshizao. I could claim Hououmaru only because you were with me for the half of my life.
여기서 편히 쉬어라.
Rest in peace.
무사시 일행은 다시 시라누이 일족의 본거를 향해 떠났다.
Musashi and others have again departed to the base of Shiranui Clan.
그렇지만 그들 앞에 기다리는 것은 꽃인가, 폭풍인가, 대분화인가!
But what will be waiting in front of them: flowers, storms, or a violent eruption?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
센짱도 참, 걱정 많이 하는 여자이오.
Sen-chan sure worries a lot-dasu!
나는 히로니까 그렇게 간단히는 안 당하오!
I'm a hero, and I don't get taken down that easily-dasu!
라고 생각했는데 혼자 시라누이 일족의 본거지를 찾고 있던 내 앞에 무서운 겐바가!
That's what I thought, but Genba has appeared in front of me during I was looking for Shiranui Clan's headquarters!
용암탄에 당한 나는 화산 안으로 풍덩!
I got hit by lava shell, and into a volcano, splash!
다음 이야기! 어라? 무사시는 죽소
Next story! What?! Musashi Dies
질풍노도의 지옥곡이오!
It's a stormy hell valley!
다음 이야기
어라?!
무사시는 죽소
재미있게 보세요!
Next Story
What?!
Musashi Dies
We hope you enjoy!